Privacy Policy
==============

[Explore This Section

Menu](# "(click to expand contents)")

* [Supplemental Privacy Notice for the European Union, United Kingdom, Iceland, Lichtenstein and Norway](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/supplemental-privacy-notice-for-the-european-union-united-kingdom-iceland-lichtenstein-and-norway/)
* [Supplemental U.S. Privacy Notice for CA, CO, CT, VA, UT, TX, MT, OR](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/supplemental-u-s-privacy-notice/)[Expand/collapse](#)

Effective: January 1, 2023

Hormel Foods Corporation or one of its wholly owned subsidiaries or joint ventures (“Company,” “our,” or “we”) owns and operates this website (our “Website”). We respect the privacy of users of our Website (“you” or “your”) and have adopted this Privacy Policy (this “Policy”) to explain what information we collect from or about you through our Website and how we use, maintain, protect, and disclose that information.

Please read this Policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information. By accessing or using our Website, except where prohibited, you agree to this Policy, which is incorporated into our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.hormelfoods.com/terms-conditions/). If you do not agree to this Policy, you may not use our Website.

**TABLE OF CONTENTS**

1. [General Policy](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#general-policy-we-respect-your)
2. [Supplemental Privacy Notices](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#2-supplemental-privacy-notices-in)
3. [What information do we collect about you?](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#3-what-information-do-we)
4. [How do we collect your information?](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#4-how-do-we-collect)
5. [How do we use your information?](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#5-how-do-we-use)
6. [What is the legal basis for our data collection?](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#6-what-is-the-legal)
7. [When do we share your information?](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#7-when-do-we-share)
8. [Where do we process your information?](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#8-where-do-we-process)
9. [How do we secure your information?](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#9-how-do-we-secure)
10. [What are your legal rights?](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#10-what-are-your-legal)
11. [How can you update your information?](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#11-how-can-you-update)
12. [How can you change your marketing preferences?](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#12-how-can-you-change)
13. [Changes to this Policy](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#13-changes-to-this-policy)
14. [Terms and Conditions](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#14-terms-and-conditions-this)
15. [Severability](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#15-severability-if-any-provision)
16. [Contact Details](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#16-contact-details-if-you)

1. **General Policy**

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your “Personal Data,” which we define as information relating to an identified or identifiable individual like you. Personal Data does not include aggregated or anonymized information, provided it does not and cannot identify you.

This Policy applies only to information we collect through our Website. Except where otherwise noted, it does not apply to information we collect through other channels. It outlines what Personal Data we collect about you through our Website and how it is used. It also explains how we process your Personal Data, who we share it with, how we look after it, and tells you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

**2\. Supplemental Privacy Notices**

In addition to the provisions in this Policy, which are generally applicable across all jurisdictions, if you are resident in one of the following locations, please review the applicable supplemental privacy notice (each a “Supplemental Privacy Notice”) linked below.

* [The European Union, United Kingdom, Iceland Lichtenstein or Norway](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/supplemental-privacy-notice-for-the-european-union-united-kingdom-iceland-lichtenstein-and-norway/)

**3\. What information do we collect about you?**

We collect information about our customers, prospective customers, vendors and business partners, and Website visitors. The type of Personal Data we collect depends on the nature of our relationship with you and the legal requirements in your location. We endeavor to collect only information that is relevant for the purposes of processing. The table below sets out the different categories of Personal Data that we may collect.

| Category of Personal Data | Representative Data Elements | Individuals to which Data Collection Applies |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Contact Information | · Name  <br>· Postal address  <br>· Telephone number  <br>·​ Email address | · End consumers  <br>· ​Vendors, customers, and other business partners |
| Unique IDs | · Customer number  <br>· Account number  <br>· Username  <br>· Device identifier  <br>· Cookie ID  <br>· Advertising ID | · End consumers  <br>· Vendors, customers, and other business partners  <br>· ​Website visitors |
| Financial Information | · Bank account number and details  <br>· Payment card information  <br>· ​Payment and reimbursement amounts | · End consumers  <br>· ​Vendors, customers, and other business partners |
| Transaction/Interaction Information | · Program registrations and subscriptions  <br>· Purchase history  <br>· Products and services considered  <br>· ​Prior communications | · End consumers  <br>· ​Vendors, customers, and other business partners |
| Demographic Information and Interests | · Age  <br>· Marital and family status  <br>· Household demographic data  <br>· Website preferences  <br>· Hobbies | · End consumers |
| Website Activity Information | · Browsing and search history  <br>· Referring website addresses  <br>· App usage data  <br>· ​Device characteristics | · End consumers  <br>· Vendors, customers, and other business partners  <br>· ​Website Visitors |

_Children Under the Age of 18._ Our Website is not intended for children under 18 years of age (or the age of majority in your jurisdiction if it is greater than 18 years of age). We do not knowingly collect, use, or disclose Personal Data from children under 18. If you believe that we have collected, used, or disclosed Personal Data of a child under the age of 18 (or the age of majority in your jurisdiction), please contact us using the contact information below so that we can take appropriate action.

**4\. How do we collect your information?**

We collect Personal Data directly from you and from other sources. The table below sets out the most common sources of Personal Data.

| Sources of Personal Data​ | Representative Collection Methods and Circumstances |
| --- | --- |
| Directly from you​ | · When you register for an account  <br>· When you submit information through a survey or contest-entry form  <br>· When you post a comment or feedback on our Website  <br>· When you contact us  <br>· ​When you purchase something through our Website |
| Through automated means | · Automatically collected as you navigate our Website |
| From third parties | · Marketing analytics service providers so that we can better understand our customers  <br>· Website analytics firms that help us improve our Website  <br>· Data aggregators from which we receive supplemental information about our customers  <br>· Through your interactions with third-party social media platforms  <br>· ​_For vendors and business partners:_ In the course of due diligence prior to contracting with you, in order to comply with regulatory requirements |

**5\. How do we use your information?**

We only use Personal Data when the law allows us to do so. We use Personal Data for the following purposes. To:

* Provide the information, products, and services you request;
* Provide you with effective customer service;
* Provide you with a personalized experience when you use our Website by delivering relevant Website content;
* Respond to your inquiries;
* Provide you with additional features on the Website based on your location;
* Contact you with information and notices related to your use of our Website;
* Send you transactional and administrative messages related to our products;
* Send you marketing communications (in accordance with your preferences);
* to invite you to participate in surveys and provide feedback to us (in accordance with any preferences you expressed to us);
* Improve the content, functionality, security and usability of our Website;
* Create insights and market intelligence (on an aggregated and non-personally identifiable basis) through analysing the use our Website and our customers;
* Provide advertisements and monitor their effectiveness;
* Monitor security and prevent fraud;
* Comply with our legal and regulatory obligations; and
* Meet other purposes notified to you through our Website, an applicable agreement or another channel.

**6\. What is the legal basis for our data collection?**

We collect Personal Data about you for a variety of purposes based on the specific legal grounds described in the table below, unless your jurisdiction requires a special legal basis for the collection of personal data (for example, consent). Please refer to the Supplemental Privacy Notice applicable to your jurisdiction for additional information.

| Purpose for Collection | Lawful Basis |
| --- | --- |
| Delivering information, content, products or services that you request or purchase | · To perform a contract or fulfill our obligation to provide products or services to you  <br>· Our legitimate interests |
| Providing marketing communications about our products and services, or those of third parties, that may be of interest to you | · Your consent  <br>· ​Our legitimate interests |
| Understanding how you use our products, services, and Website in order to improve and further develop our products and services and the content, features, performance, and support available through our Websites | · Our legitimate interests |
| Providing legal or service-related notices about our products, services, and Websites | · To perform a contract with you  <br>· Our legitimate interests  <br>· ​To comply with a legal obligation |
| Detecting, preventing, and responding to fraud, intellectual property infringement, violations of our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.hormelfoods.com/terms-conditions/), violations of law, or other misuse of the Websites | · Our legitimate interests  <br>· ​To comply with a legal obligation |
| Protecting our rights or the rights, property, and safety of others | · Our legitimate interests  <br>· To comply with a legal obligation |
| Complying with laws and regulations, judicial and administrative orders, or lawful requests from governmental authorities | · ​To comply with a legal obligation |
| Conducting due diligence prior to entering into a contract with you | · Your consent  <br>· To perform a contract with you  <br>· ​Our legitimate interests |
| Processing your application for employment with us, including administration of the recruitment process and evaluation of your candidacy | · Your consent  <br>· To perform a contract with you  <br>· Our legitimate interests  <br>· ​To comply with a legal obligation |
| Paying you for services you have provided to us, providing you with benefits to which you are entitled, or reimbursing you for expenses | · To perform a contract with you |

We may combine or aggregate any Personal Data we collect for any of the above purposes.  We may also anonymize your Personal Data in such a way that you may not be re-identified by us or any other organization. We may use such anonymized information for any purpose.

**7\. When do we share your information?**

We share your Personal Data with third parties for the purposes listed below.

| Category of Third Party | Representative Purposes for Disclosure | Safeguards |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Other members of the Hormel Corporate family | · For the functions and activities described above concerning the purposes for which we collect your Personal Data | All Hormel entities are required to comply with this Privacy Policy. |
| Service providers _(contractors, professional advisors, insurers, finance providers or external auditors)_ | · To assist us in the functions and activities described above concerning the purposes for which we collect your Personal Data, including:  <br>o IT support, cloud platform and data hosting services to support the operation of our websites, mobile applications, document and workflow management systems and other systems and applications.  <br>o Payment processing.  <br>o Assistance with supply chain logistics and delivery of products you have requested/ordered.  <br>o Customer service activities, including managing queries and complaints.  <br>o Marketing support, including sending out email and other communications on our behalf.  <br>o ​Record-keeping and reporting to assist us in complying with laws and industry standards. | Hormel executes contracts with service providers prohibiting them from using or sharing your Personal Data except as necessary to perform the contracted services on our behalf or to comply with applicable legal requirements. |
| Marketing Partners | · To jointly offer products or services | Hormel executes contracts with business partners that requires them to protect your Personal Data, and, where required by applicable laws, your Personal Data is only shared with your explicit consent. |
| Successor-in-interest _(actual or proposed)_ | · To continue to perform the functions and activities described above concerning the purposes for which we collect your Personal Data in the event of a proposed or actual purchase, any reorganization, sale, lease, merger, joint venture, assignment, amalgamation or any other type of acquisition, disposal or financing of all or any portion of our business or of any of the business assets or shares (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceeding) | Hormel will endeavor to direct the transferee to use PersonalData in a manner that is consistent with this Policy. |
| Regulatory authorities and law enforcement agencies | · Where necessary for any investigations or to respond to enquiries in relation to our compliance with applicable law or regulations  <br>· ​Where we, in good faith, believe disclosure is appropriate to prevent or investigate a possible crime, or to protect the security of our personnel or property, or the personnel or property of others | We endeavor to limit such disclosures to the minimum necessary and to obtain assurances that your Personal Data will be protected. |
| Judicial authorities and parties to judicial proceedings | · To respond to a court order or other binding request | We endeavor to limit such disclosures to the minimum necessary and to obtain assurances that your Personal Data will be protected. |

We do not sell your Personal Data. Nor do we share your Personal Data with third parties for their own marketing purposes, except with your consent and in connection with a jointly offered product or service.

We may disclose your Personal Data to anyone to whom disclosure is necessary to fulfill the purpose for which you provided the Personal Data. For example, if you give us an e-mail address to use the “e-mail a friend” feature of our Website, we will transmit the contents of that e-mail and your e-mail address to the recipients.

_Aggregated Information_. We share aggregated information about our users (e.g., statistical or demographic data) for any purpose. Such information could be derived from your Personal Data, but it no longer identifies you directly or indirectly. For example, we may aggregate usage data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific Website feature. However, if we combine or connect aggregated information with your Personal Data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined information as Personal Data which will be used in accordance with this Policy.

_User Contributions_. Content you post to the Website or in interactions with us through the social networking tools we make available to you (“User Contributions”), including those that contain Personal Data, are publicly accessible. In particular, please note that User Contributions, by definition, can be read, collected, used, and further disclosed by other users of our Website. Please refer to our Terms and Conditions for more information about User Contributions. We strongly recommend you avoid sharing any personal details, and especially information that can be used to identify you directly such as your name, age, address and name of employer, in your User Contributions. We do not control how third parties who may access this publicly accessible information may use your User Contributions. We may use User Contributions for advertising campaigns and other promotions, and we share User Contributions with third parties for such purposes. Where such advertising campaigns or promotions involve Personal Data connected to your User Contribution, we will seek your consent before using the information.

_Links to Other Websites._ Our Website may contain links to third-party websites or other online platforms. Clicking on these links may allow third parties to collect or share information about you. These links are provided for your reference and convenience only and do not imply any endorsement of the products sold or information provided through these websites, nor any association with their operators. We do not control these websites and we are not responsible for their data practices or privacy statements. Any information you provide to third parties on their websites is covered under their privacy and data collection policies and is not covered by this Policy. We urge you to review the privacy policy posted on any website you visit before using the website or providing any personally identifiable information.

Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, and other social media platforms provide tools that many of our customers use and enjoy, and we include links to various social media platforms on our Website. If you interact with these social media platforms through our Website, including with our profiles on these platforms, your experience on those platforms will be governed by the privacy and other policies of those platforms. We encourage you to choose your privacy settings on those websites accordingly. If you log into our Website using your credentials from a social media platform, that platform also may receive data about the pages or content that you viewed on our Website.

_Third-Party Analytics Tools_. Beyond the information you voluntarily provide to us directly, we utilize analytics tools, including third-party technologies such as Google Analytics, to collect information and help us understand how visitors engage with our Website. To learn more about Google Analytics, click [here](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html). To learn more about how Google uses data collected through partner websites or applications, click [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).

Please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.hormelfoods.com/online-cookie-policy/) for more information about the use of different tracking techniques on our website.

_Third-Party Advertising Tools._ Third parties may deliver cookies or other tracking technologies, including web beacons or tracking pixels, to your computer or mobile device for the purpose of tracking your online behaviors across nonaffiliated websites, and to deliver targeted advertisements on other nonaffiliated websites.

Please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.hormelfoods.com/online-cookie-policy/) for more information about the use of different tracking techniques on our website.

**8\. Where do we process your information?**

Your Personal Data may be stored and processed in your country, but it may also be transferred to or viewed in another country, including the U.S., where allowed by applicable laws. Hormel is part of a global company, and we may transfer your Personal Data in compliance with applicable laws to a recipient in another jurisdiction, or receive your Personal Data from another jurisdiction, if one of the following protections applies:

* The recipient is located in a jurisdiction in which the laws ensure a level of data protection that is equivalent to those in jurisdiction where data was collected.
* The recipient is subject to an approved certification mechanism or code of conduct with binding and enforceable commitments that provide appropriate safeguards for your Personal Data.
* We have put in place appropriate contractual safeguards to protect your Personal Data.
* The transfer to a foreign jurisdiction is expressly permitted by applicable laws.
* You explicitly consent to the transfer.

**9\. How do we secure your information?**

We have put in place reasonable security measures to prevent your Personal Data from unlawful or unauthorized processing and accidental loss, destruction, alteration or damage. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet can never be completely secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the security of your Personal Data. Any transmission of Personal Data is at your own risk. Subject to applicable law, we are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Website.

_Data Retention._ We will retain your Personal Data for as long as is necessary for the purposes listed in this Policy unless a longer period is required under applicable law, or a longer period is needed to resolve disputes or protect our legal rights or otherwise comply with legal obligations.

When assessing the data retention period, we take into account the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of the data, the purposes for which we process the data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

**10\. What are your legal rights?**

In certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your Personal Data. Your rights may vary depending on the country in which you live, or the country in which we process your information. Please refer to the appropriate Supplemental Privacy Notice, see “[Supplemental Privacy Notices](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#2-supplemental-privacy-notices-in),” Section 2, that is applicable to you for rights specific to your location. If you wish to exercise any of the rights set forth in the applicable Supplemental Privacy Notice, see “[Supplemental Privacy Notices,](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#2-supplemental-privacy-notices-in)” Section 2, or to learn more about such rights, please contact us as indicated below.

**11\. How can you update your information?**

Please contact us, as indicated below, see “[Contact Details](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/#16-contact-details-if-you),” Section 16.

**12\. How can you change your marketing preferences?**

In General. We respect your right to make choices about the ways in which we collect, use, and disclose your Personal Data. We may ask you to indicate your choices at the time and on the page where you provide your information. Our [Cookie Policy](https://www.hormelfoods.com/online-cookie-policy/) describes additional choices, such as your choice to opt out of receiving “cookies”.

_Opt-in or Opt-out Mechanism._ In relation to marketing communications (including promotional emails), we may provide you with an “opt-in” or “opt-out” mechanism depending on where in the world you are located. An “opt-in” mechanism will provide you the opportunity to positively indicate that you agree to our sending you such further communications. An “opt-out” mechanism will provide you the opportunity to indicate that you do not want us to send you such further communications, and if you “opt-out” we will not send you any additional such communications.

_Email preferences._ You can opt out of promotional emails we send you. If you wish to stop receiving promotional emails, simply select “unsubscribe” located at the bottom of each communication. Please note that you cannot opt out of transactional emails, such as emails confirming a purchase made on our Website.

_Previously Expressed Preferences._ You may be able to change previously expressed preferences regarding how we use your information. To do so, please contact us using the contact information provided below.

**13\. Changes to this Policy**

We are continually improving and adding to the features and functionality of this Website, and to the services we offer through this Website. As a result of these changes (or changes in the law), we may need to update or revise this Policy. Accordingly, we reserve the right to update or modify this Policy at any time, without prior notice (unless prohibited in your jurisdiction), by posting the revised version of this Policy behind the link marked “Privacy Policy” at the bottom of each page of this Website. Your continued use of this Website after we have posted the revised Policy constitutes your agreement to be bound by the revised Policy. However, we will honor the terms that were in effect when we gathered data from you. We will also endeavor, where feasible, to notify you in advance of significant and material changes to this Policy.

For your convenience, whenever this Policy is changed, we will update the “Revised on” at the top of this page. Be sure you check the “Revised on” date to see if this Policy has been revised since your last visit.

You may access the current version of this Policy at any time by clicking the link marked “Privacy Policy” at the bottom of each page of this Website.

**14\. Terms and Conditions**

This Policy and any applicable Supplemental Privacy Notices are incorporated into the [Terms and Conditions](https://www.hormelfoods.com/terms-conditions/) that govern your use of this Website. If you do not agree to abide by the Term and Conditions, you may not access or use this Website.

**15\. Severability**

If any provision of this Policy, including a Supplemental Privacy Notice, is declared invalid or unenforceable by a court having competent jurisdiction, that provision will be removed from the Policy without affecting the rest of the Policy, and the remaining provisions of the Policy shall continue to be valid and enforceable.

**16\. Contact Details**

If you have any questions about this Policy or our privacy practices, please contact us at:

Hormel Foods Corporation  
1 Hormel Place  
Austin, MN 55912  
Attn: Legal Department – Privacy

Email: [privacy@hormel.com](https://www.hormelfoods.com/privacy-policy/privacy@hormel.com)
